[Music]
Hello friends, welcome to our
YouTube channel. When you go to buy a plan, you are
told about these products in the form of comparison, such as your
Reshot of NB, your Optima Secure of ADAC.
If you talk about Money Pal plan, then
Prime product comes in it. So
today we will learn complete information about all these plans
so that you
can know which plan will be suitable for your family
and what is your budget, which one has
more features.
Today we will completely analyze all these things so
that you can know which plan
is more suitable for you. Friends, if you are
new to our channel, then
subscribe to our channel right now. Press the bell icon
so that
you can get notifications of upcoming videos on time.
Apart from this, let me tell you that
we keep bringing content for you on a regular basis
so that you can make your financial journey
smooth. Further, I want to tell you
that if you want to keep your wealth and health
better, then please subscribe to our channel.
So let's
go to our screen and understand the difference between these three plans.
First of all, we will talk about the
cover option. We have chosen the one-year tenure
option. The premium for ADFC Optima Secure is
approximately Rs.
26,100. In Niva Bhupa, your approximate premium is Rs. 18,400.
And in Maval Cigna, it is approximately Rs.
19,800.
Before telling about the top features, let me
tell you that we have compared these three plans for
two adults
and have chosen the pin code of Delhi, that is,
metro cities.
We have chosen the sum cover option of Rs. 10 lakh. Here we are talking about the
top features. So, in ADFC, we are
talking about special features.
Here, the secure benefit means that it
intentionally makes the base sum double at no
extra cost. This means that the company is
charging you an extra premium. So,
in a policy of Rs. 10 lakh, you get a
benefit of up to Rs. 20 lakh from day one.  It is giving
you this by default in this product,
which is covered under the special feature
Protect Benefit means
that 68 of your non-payable items are covered without any
extra cost. Whatever non-payable
items are there, which we call consumable items, in
which other companies
charge you extra premium in the
name of rider, so here your non-consumable
items, which are non-payable items, are
covered, in which
you do not have to pay any extra cost,
plus you get Plus Benefit, in
respect of the claim, you get 50% of the bonus
every year maximum of up to 100%, which
means that if you take this plan today, then
next year the policy of 10 lakhs that you have taken under it will become 15 lakhs and
from 15 lakhs to 20 lakhs. You get the no claim bonus
feature by default in it.
Now let's talk about e-opinion in available,
here your e-opinion of 51 critical illnesses
You also get the option in case
you have any critical illness and you
think where should I get treatment, how much will the
treatment cost,
which hospital is better, then you
can take e-opinion for this from the company, their
team of expert doctors will
guide you through e-opinion so that
you can get rid of your critical illness,
so these are the features in your ADAC,
now let's talk about nb, so nbhop's
live healthy benefit means that you
get a discount on renewal up to 30 percent,
if you walk 7 km on a daily basis,
then the company will make available to you the benefit of up to 30 percent,
if you
take this plan, you get one day one health checkup in nb, that
means
if you are taking a policy of 10 lakhs today,
then you can avail the benefit of health checkup up to 5000 in it,
which is 500 per day,
which the company also mentions in the brochure.
If you
want to avail this through cashless mode,
you can also avail its cashless benefit by downloading the NV mobile application. You will be able to avail
health
checkup from day one. If
you have taken an insurance policy, then
after this you can log in to your mobile application after your policy.
Here, let's
talk about Money Bal Cigna. Here you get
unlimited tele-consultation cover. You get
switch-off benefit optional
from day one and maximum up
to 30 days. If you are going abroad, that is, to
any place outside India or for any
business purpose,
then you can
avail your switch-on and switch-off option within this plan. This
means that if you are
going out of India from Delhi for 10 days,
then you can stop its benefit for 10 days. The
premium of your policy will be
extended by 10 days. After 10 days, you will be
able to avail this benefit, which means
that your premium will be saved here.  You
also get premium waiver benefit for 10 days.
Premium waiver on the
accidental death and diagnosis of any
critical illness. Now here the company
gives you a feature by default that your
premium will be waived for a certain
time, which you can see in the policy brochure and
wording on accidental death
and diagnosis of any critical illness. If
any fatal disease occurs or any
accidental death occurs, then in that case
your premium will be waived.
If your family member is covered under the policy, then
they do not need to pay any separate premium in future,
which will remain till the certain time limit. You can see the
policy word and then the policy brochure.
So here I will tell you, let us
talk further about the restoration benefit,
which is your restoration benefit. Let us
talk about it in all the three plans. It is
triggered by SDFC once in a policy year,
partially or fully exhausted, meaning that it will
trigger only then. Your registration
benefit here  Once you claim it, you
can either claim it partially.
Suppose if it is a policy of Rs 10 lakh, then you
claim Rs 2 lakh or you
fully exhaust it by taking a total claim of Rs 10 lakh.
So
what is this restoration benefit? In a policy of Rs 10 lakh,
you can reclaim the benefit of Rs 10 lakh in the same year,
but the
condition is that you will
go home after being discharged and only if there is a need for it again,
we can give you the benefit of registration.
In Niva BAP, you can partially and fully
exhaust it. Here
you can cover unlimited time-related and unrelated illnesses. This
means that if you are
taking a policy of Rs 10 lakh, you
need Rs 10 lakh again.
After being discharged, you go home and after that, if
you need health insurance again, then you
can take the benefit of Rs 10 lakh again. So, by
following this process, you can reclaim it multiple
times, that is, unlimited.  You
can use the times, which the company
also mentions on the plan brochure. Okay, if we
talk about Manipal, then your unlimited times will
trigger after partial and full
exhaustion. Now in SDAC, you will
get it only once in a policy year. If there is a 10-year
policy of Rs. 10 lakh, then you get the benefit of Rs. 10 lakh once.
In Niva VOP, you get unlimited times benefit
and in Manipal also you get the
benefit of unlimited times. Okay, let's
move ahead and talk about pre-
hospitalization. If pre-hospitalization is
seen, then normally it is of
60 days in HDFC Niva Bhupa and Manipal.
Whenever you are admitted in the hospital, then
whatever expenses are there before that,
suppose you consulted a doctor or
you took some medicines etc. or
you got some reports done etc., then
you can collect all those bills and give them to the company
and get its reburn amount back
in your bank account. So
this pre-hospitalization  You get hospitalization facility up to 60 days
in all three companies with the same
options and same conditions.
In post-hospitalization, you are given 180 days in all
three companies.
So,
you can avail the benefit of up to 180 days here.
Whenever you are discharged from the hospital and go home, then
somewhere or the other we
need to see the doctor again. Some
reports may need to be done, some
medicines may be required. So whatever
our expenses are relevant to that
particular,
what can we do? We
can get back all the bills from the insurance company on a remembrance basis,
which we can also know as post-hospitalization claim.
Okay, so let's move ahead to
No Claim Bonus. No Claim Bonus
means that there is a plus benefit here which is
available on 50% of the sum assured and
you can claim a maximum of up to 100% of the No Claim
Bonus.  You can avail the benefit of a policy worth Rs 10 lakh and
after Rs 15 lakh,
you get a benefit of up to Rs 20 lakh in the next year. HDFC Bank plans give you a
booster benefit. If no claim is
made in the proceeding policy,
the base sum should increase by Rs 50 per month subject to
a maximum of 100%. Now, in this plan also, you get a
no-claim bonus benefit of Rs 50 per month, which is up to a
maximum of 100%. If
you take the Titanium Plus plan here, then let
me tell you that this
benefit of no-claim bonus becomes your booster
plus benefit, which means that
you get just double in this, that is, a policy worth Rs 10 lakh will just
double to Rs 20 lakh,
after Rs 20 lakh it will become Rs 30 lakh and this maximum goes up to Rs 1
crore. Its benefit keeps increasing 10 times
year on year.
If you talk about Manpal,
then here  But you
get your benefit on your policy of Rs 2.5 lakh, which means there is a no
claim bonus of 25% and the maximum
increase is up to 10%. In this
Manpal plan, if we talk about
room rent, then your actual room rent is available in ADFC, which
means that
whatever actual expenses are there in the
name of your room rent in the hospital, you
can claim them here completely. And
in Niva Bhupa, you
can take any kind of any category of room here,
whether it is deluxe, super deluxe or
you are taking any private room or suite
room, then you can take it here.
In Manpal also, you can select any category of room
here for your
hospitalization claim. Okay, let's
move ahead to the base coverages. In the base coverages,
your cashless hospital comes. If we
talk about SGFC, then there are 442 cashless
hospitals in your area, for which I have
selected the pin code here.  There are
442 or more than 400 cashless hospitals
available in it. If you talk about Niva, there
are 262 cashless hospitals available and if you
talk about Manipal, there are 298 cashless hospitals available.
I had
mentioned the pin code while calculating the premium here. So if we are
talking about all three, then the maximum
cashless hospital facility, which is network
hospital, is with ADFC. So
if you consider ADFC policy, you may have to
pay a little more premium,
but for that you
also get a list of cashless hospitals or
more network hospitals. Let's move ahead to
claim settlement ratio. Now,
in ADFC, you will see that our claim
settlement ratio is 99. Even if we
talk about Niva, it is 92 and
in Manipal, you can see that it is 93. So, if we
compare all three, it is at 99
in ADFC. So, if you have
no concern about the premium, no concern about the budget, then
you can consider SDFC.  You can go with this plan
by comparing it and
go to the claim settlement option at Rs. 99. Okay, let's
move ahead and understand the day care
procedure. Now what is the day care procedure?
Due to technology advancement, all the
treatments that are done in 3 hours, 4 hours, 5 hours are
covered under your day care here. So HDFC also provides
you day care cover. Here
Niva also provides you all day care cover.
And in Manipal also you get the same option, that is,
you can take day care cover. Okay, if we
talk about co-payment, then there will be no
limit on any type of disease here, there will be no co-
payment.
You get an HDFC plan with no co-payment.
In Niva Bhupa also you do
not have any limit, there is no co-payment.
And if you talk about Manipal, then
if you come from Zone 2 to Zone 1, now let me
explain to you, the metro cities
come under Zone 1, which are a little non-network,
which we can call Tier 2 cities like
Lucknow.  Or if I talk about
Lucknow or let's say you are in
Kerala, then in this way
all your areas come under your zone two, the
rest varies from company to company,
you can see the policy brochure or the policy
wording that
which
areas and cities come under zone one, zone two, zone three, okay, so if you come to zone one from zone two, then
your copayment is 10%, if you come to
zone two from zone three, then
your copayment is 10%,
but if you come directly from zone three to zone one and
claim, then
you have to pay 20% of every claim
from your pocket, so make sure that whenever you buy a policy, there is
no zone wise capping in your policy, do
check this once, okay,
so let's move ahead, ambulance charges,
ambulance charges, under HDFC you are covered
100% of the hospitalization, your road
ambulance is covered, okay, air
ambulance, you get full hospitalization cover up to Rs 5 lakh
Under SDFC and Niva Bhupa, you get up to sum
coverage for your road ambulance and
up to 22.5 lakh for your
hospitalization. If we
talk about Manipal, then air ambulance is covered up to
sum coverage subject to the
maximum of 10 lakh over and above base sum coverage, which
means that you get air ambulance cover in it. So let's
talk about
maternity cover. If we talk about maternity cover, then
in all the three plans, whether it is
SGFC, Niva or Muffle,
you get not covered in all the three plans. Even after paying
any extra premium with any riders,
you cannot get maternity cover in all the three plans. So,
it is not covered in all the three plans.
Moving ahead,
if you talk about domicile treatment in SDFC, then here
you get covered up to sum coverage, which means
that your treatment up to 10 lakh is covered.
It is covered in Niva Bhu as well.
They have not mentioned it, but I am talking about the fact that
it should also be shown in your brochure that
you get domicile treatment cover. If we
talk about Manipal, then here you can
avail a benefit of up to ₹10,000 only. In these
cases, if you want to
avail the benefit of domicile treatment, let's talk about
network hospital daily cash. If you
take a plan under HDFC, then if
you take a shared room, then here you get a per day benefit of
₹1 in the form of cash. If you are taking a policy of ₹10,00,000 or less or if you are taking a policy of ₹15 lakh or more, then you get a benefit of ₹1
for a maximum of six days. So,
if you avail their shared room, if you
go to a shared room instead of a single room, then the company makes this benefit available to you in the form of cash.
So,
in Niva, this will not be available in the plan, it
is not available and this
option is not available in Manipal also.  You will not be paid
any amount in the form of daily cash hospital.
Now let us talk about
some waiting periods. Whenever
we take a policy for the first time, then at that time there is
some initial waiting period, specific
waiting period plus pre-existence disease.
If we have any chronic disease, then
we can get it covered too, but the
insurance company covers it only after some time. So first of all let us
talk about SDFC. The
waiting period of pre-existence disease in SDFC is 36 months, which
means that after 3 years, if you are
undergoing any problem treatment surgery, then
after 3 years we will cover you in the insurance company.
Specific disease
waiting period which is like
joint replacement, hernia, pyelitis,
cataract, gastric problem, for these types of
diseases the company covers you after 24 months, which means that
whenever you
take an initial policy, there is also an initial
waiting period so that you
cannot make a claim from the immediate insurance company.  You can do this,
so its initial waiting period is of one month, that is,
you can claim any
urgent or emergency incident,
any injury or
any problem from the
insurance company, you get all the
three benefits in Niva,
PD waiting period is of 36 months,
specific disease waiting period is of 24
months and your initial waiting period is of
one month, if you
talk about Manpal, then your PD waiting period is of
24 months, specific disease waiting period is of 24 months
and your
initial waiting period is of one month, if you
see in comparison of all three, then
in Manpal, PD means that the problem which you are going to face first is
covered before one year, the company covers it in 2 years
itself, in the other two plans
you get cover after 3 years, let's talk about it  Regarding
health wellness,
you will see health wellness benefit somewhere
in the plan in the name of value added cover,
so in ADAC, no such option
or any such benefit is made available,
but in nv, you
can avail its benefit at the time of premium renewal in the form of discount.
If you are taking a family floater, then
you get the benefit of up to 15 per cent.
If you are taking an individual plan, then
you can avail its benefit of up to 30 per cent, in
which the company says that
you have to walk or run 7 km daily, for
which we will fetch your data from your application
and on that basis your
renewal will be decided whether you may get the
discount or not,
so make sure that whenever you are
taking an nv product or if you already have an
nv plan, then you can definitely know about its benefits by
downloading the mobile application.
So here we talk about the benefits
under Money Pal Cigna.
Rewards up to 20 per cent of the base premium
through the completion of the Health Life
Management Programme. They basically offer you a
management programme
through which if you run any of your health programmes
or
follow their terms and conditions through the management programme,
then the company gives you reward points up to 20 per cent
which you can encash
even on renewal of premium or on filling it,
you can
avail its benefit. Let's talk about
organ donor, in all those three plans
your organ donor is
covered up to some extent, whether it is ADFC,
Niva Bapa or Manpal Cigna. Okay, even
Niva has not mentioned it here,
but if you look at their plan brochure, then
they also provide you the organ donor benefit. Let's
talk about the
policy brochure and word, so here the policy
brochures and the policy
word, definitely look at it once
whenever you go to buy a policy.  Yes, so at least
you can see their terms and conditions, what are the benefits in them, you
can see all those things in complete information,
although I will not be able to cover all the things in this video
because what is
suitable for you, is the family suitable for you, is the
premium suitable for you, which plan will be
best for you and your family,
you can judge all those things by sitting with an advisor in one to one consultation somewhere and you
can also secure your family by taking advice from them,
so friends, let me tell you that whatever
we have discussed in these plans is
seen somewhere or the other, so among these three products,
I preferred HDFC because
here you get
double benefit from day one, if we talk about
claim settlement, then
you get the product with claim settlement at Rs.99,
although you will have to pay a little
more premium in this, thirdly, if you talk about
consumable items,
non-payable items, you get these by default,  If
you get it, then considering all these things, I would recommend SDFC to you. If you want
information about any other plan, then you
can also check the brochure for complete details of this product.
Their brochure or policy
listing, I will
also put it in my description link, so that you
can check it out by going there also. So
friends, how did you like the video, quickly
like and share it so that more people can get complete
information about these three products. And if you also want to
get information about these three products or any other health insurance plan, then in the description
box I will give you a link so that
you can connect with me by calling for one to one consultation
and secure your family.
So friends, now we will
meet.  In the next video, Till the Time Be
Safe Be In Short
[Music]